Leah: What is Agile development?
Chris: Let’s have a look
at this in more detail.
Leah: ‘Agile Development’ which is
also more commonly known as Agile
Software Development, is an umbrella
term for a range of frameworks,
such as ‘Scrum’, and practices such
as the ‘daily stand-up meeting’.
It adopts the principles set
out in the ‘Agile Manifesto’
and the ‘Agile 12 Principles’.
Chris: The Agile Manifesto is a
short document, which was created
in 2001 from a group of leading
professionals who met to discuss
the future of software development.
Its focus is on value to individuals and
interactions, working software, customer
collaboration and responding to change.
The Manifesto itself is short and
made up of 68 words and has since
been embraced by many different teams
and companies, and it is agreed by
many that it is still relevant today.
Leah: The 12 Principles of Agile Software,
expand on the values within the Manifesto.
The focus is on the customer,
continuous delivery of product,
change, frequency, team collaboration,
motivation, support, communication,
measurement, excellence, simplicity,
self-organisation, and reflection.
Agile came about as a process to
address issues that software developers
faced, focussing on a project being
flexible, so it could respond to any
changes and deal with any uncertainty.
Chris: Agile is people-oriented and
result-focused in respect to software
delivery and instead of delivering all
the product at the end of the project,
the software is built incrementally
from the start in time-boxed 'sprints'.
It is an iterative approach used in
software development projects with a
focus on continuous releases that takes
customer feedback into consideration.
Development tasks are broken down into
bite size chunks, which can be achieved
in a certain period known as a ‘sprint’.
Each task would be assigned a
measurement of time or complexity.
The self-organised agile team itself would
normally consist of different skillsets,
working independently and collaboratively,
to achieve the tasks within that set time.
Leah: Agile development’s iterative
approach means that continuous testing
and continuous improvement takes place
throughout the entire product lifecycle
this gives early warnings of quality
issues, reduces the risk of failure,
and gives opportunities to find new ways
to fix those issues and or processes.
There is an emphasis on frequent
continuous releases with customer
transparency and visibility
on the work in progress.
Chris: Project planning is also
ongoing throughout the project
which is known as just-in-time
[also a method used in ‘LEAN’].
Estimates for each stage or
‘Sprint’ are relative and these are
refined as the project progresses.
Features also begin more general
and details are added later.
As not all the details are available
at the beginning of the project,
features being added later are
often influenced by other members
or the team and the customer.